Rachel A. Dowdy

Whether I am working directly with your data, or building the front-end, I will take to it quickly and efficiently. I am a fast learner and work well in groups or alone. Since my education thus far has been on the topics of many things at once, I am capable of being a flexible asset to suit your needs. **SEE MORE ON MY WEBSITE**:

https://radowtay.github.io/webpage-practice/index.html

EXPERIENCE

Northside ISD, Folks Middle School — Orchestra Director

July 2017 - November 2021

Many jobs, including inventory, accounting, data engineering, administrative duties, lesson planning, newsletter creation, department event calendar management, source private lesson teachers, event planning, mass communication to parents, students and administration, 200+ student program

Basis.ed, BASIS San Antonio Medical Center — Orchestra/Choir Director

July 2015 - 2017

Recruit and grow program; build library; event planning and logistics; lesson planning

Terra Nova Violins, San Antonio — Studio Administrator

May 2013 - July 2014

Manage studio schedule; recruit students and match with appropriate instrument teacher; mass communication; manage scheduling and appointments; clean and decorate studios; customer service

Self-Employed Freelance Musician and Teacher

2008 - Current

EDUCATION

Rice University via UTSA, Online Data Analytics Bootcamp — *Certificate soon!*

November 2021 - June 2022 (CURRENT)

Data Analytics Bootcamp: VBA, Excel macros, Python, Jupyter Notebook, GitHub, Matplotlib, pandas, Leaflet, JavaScript, HTML-5, Bootstrap, CSS, APIs, Flask

University of Texas at San Antonio — *Music, with focus in Education*

August 2008 - May 2013

9801 Boulder Hill Street, San Antonio, TX 78250

(210)415-5487 racheladowdy@gmail.com

LANGUAGES AND ENVIRONMENTS

- pgAdmin
- SQL
- noSQL
- Tableau
- Python
- pandas, Matplotlib, and many other libraries
- Jupyter Notebook
- JavaScript
- HTML and CSS
- Bootstrap
- Visual Studio Code
- Leaflet
- MongoDB
- Flask
- Tableau
- Excel and VBA, pivot tables
- APIs

PROJECTS

Leaflet Earthquake Project — html, css, Javascript, API, Leaflet

https://github.com/radowtay/leaflet-challenge

Tableau Citi-Bike Project— *Tableau*

https://github.com/radowtay/tableau-project

Paranormal Traffic Webpage — SQL, Flask, html, css, Python, Javascript, API, Leaflet

https://github.com/radowtay/Project_3

Pymaceuticals Analysis — *Jupyter Notebook, Python, Matplotlib*

https://github.com/radowtay/matplotlib-challen ge

SQL Employer Analysis — *SQL*, pgAdmin, data engineering

https://github.com/radowtay/sql-challenge

Weather Findings Webpage — Jupyter Notebook, pandas, html, Bootstrap

https://github.com/radowtay/Web-Design-Chall enge